HIMANSHU NAMDEO

Himanshunamdeo5@gmail.com 8087244472



Summary

An iOS Application Developer with 6 years and 4 months of rich hands-on experience of iOS application development in horizontals like Hospitality, Entertainment, Health Care, E-Commerce, and all levels of testing, including performance, functional and user acceptance.

Education

Aug 2012 – Feb 2013	Post Graduate Diploma in Mobile Computing	Sunbeam Institute of Information Technology	CDAC	78%
2008 – 2012	BE Computer Science and Engineering	S. B. Jain Institute of Technology Management and Research	Nagpur University	60.33%
2007	12 th	Kendriya Vidyalaya Ajni Nagpur	CBSE	69%
2005	10 th	Kendriya Vidyalaya Ajni Nagpur	CBSE	78%

Relevant Work Experience

Cybage Software Pvt. Ltd.

March 2013 – Dec 2015

Fairmont Raffles Hotels International:

- Royal Service Mobile Application: RSM-App is an enterprise application
 developed for the employees of the Hotel. This application allows the employees
 to get the requests raised by the checked in guests On the Go on their iOS
 devices.
- **Event Service Module**: RSM-App with a feature of enlisting the functions to be held in the property on a particular day and creating requests for the events taking place for that particular function with chatting functionality.
- **Service Recovery Module**: RSM-App with a feature of creating the request for those requests that were reported by the guest as unsatisfied or incomplete. This feature was implemented to recover the concern raised by the guest against the service of the hotel.

Ansh Systems Jan 2016 – Nov 2016

- **Movie Smash:** This was the application with a feature of dubbing a video clip with your voice in different pitches, saving and sharing it afterwards.
- **Media Lab:** It is a file sharing application via cloud. It displays all the files uploaded to the cloud with same folder structure as in the cloud. File sharing is done via email.

Himanshu Namdeo - Resume

Prorigo Software Pvt. Ltd. Jan 2017 – Aug 2018

- **SmartBooking:** It is an UI rich application which statistically displays the financial data of the user's company. This application uses various UI representations to display the data like tables, graphs etc.
- **Jewelfie:** An enterprise ecommerce application dedicated to Jewelries, with every features that a normal ecommerce application contains with a special feature of trying the jewelries virtually on the application on customer's selfies, hence the name.
- **Tumor Board:** An end user application targeting the medical practitioners pursuing their practice in Cancer treatment. The application is a forum application where a user can create a particular case related to oral cancer and invite other doctors to analyze the case and give there feedback on it.
- Care Cloud: An appointment management application for US based users. This application ease out the requirement of the patients to fill up the forms before checking in.
- **Bandhu:** A three application project developed for the collaboration of Fleet Owner, Driver, and Mechanic towards meeting a goal of maintenance, service bill tracking, event reporting, Job card maintenance etc.
- Ascent Cyber Solution Pitney Bowes(Consultan t)
- **DesignSystem:** A framework that brands the application its embedded in into the Pitney Bowes standardized theme.
- Analytics Framework: A framework that is developed to make the
 implementation of different Analytics tool to operate from a single hub. Any
 number of available Analytics Framework can be integrated in the application
 and all of the functionality of all those tools can be operated from this framework
 with only one function call.
- **Authentication SDK**: A framework that acts as a HUB for multiple IDPs. Currently supports Okta and Google.

Skill Set

Aug 2018 -

Present

Language Native iOS(Objective C, Swift), React Native

Platform iOS, Android

OS Windows, Mac OSX, Linux

Tools Xcode, Eclipse, Android Studio, Visual Studio, Visual Source Safe, Team Foundation

Server, Unity, Git, Jira, CodeClimate.

Himanshu Namdeo - Resume

Personal Information

Father's Name Harkishan Namdeo

Mother's Name Rajkumari Namdeo

Sex Male
Nationality Indian

Languages English, Hindi

Known

Marital Status Married

Date of Birth 02-04-1989

Address Rachana Madhuban Apartments, C-Wing Flat 212, Mankapur, Faras, Nagpur.

I hereby declare that the information provided above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place:

Date: Himanshu Namdeo